NATANAEL MOTA

nat.c.mota@gmail.com

9 079 468 49 227

Fitzrovia, London

in linkedin.com/in/natanaelmota-b15b653a



PRODUCT MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST

With a five year track record in product strategy, discovery, and cross-functional execution in B2B and B2C in Marketing, Fintech, and Payments, I excel in communicating complex concepts with clarity and precision. My analytical skills are particularly valuable in navigating new initiatives, using the customer's voice to deliver on time and budget.



ACHIEVEMENTS

ometria Product Manager

Jun 2022 - Present

Condon

£2'000'000

 Led Ometria's website personalisation discovery in a new market for the company, resulting in a **2M GBP** decision by the executive team

• Introduced pre-mortems and future press releases to development

 Build and expand EMEA and NA technical partnerships in Ometria's ecosystem of 8 technical partnerships and more than 20 integrations

Investment decision for entering new market I quantified for Ometria

450

Hours saved per month for Dispute Operations in first two quarters

66%

faster VISA RTSI integration vs retail banks using Agile at Checkout.com

£100'000

Google Analytics 360 yearly fee I saved LendInvest with API pipeline

Cross functional teams that I have taught advanced Google Analytics to

Software Engineering teams I have managed and improved processes of

1

IEEE Nuclear Physics paper I was coauthor of during my Masters

Aug 2020 - Jun 2022

Condon

- Led VISA RTSI integration project from discovery to execution. 450 hours per month in Operations time were saved in first two quarters
- Led monthly Dispute analytics discussion using automated python reports leveraging Looker, Plotly and Facebook Prophet
- Used data-led stories to get and lead key user interviews with some of our largest and busiest clients like Cripto.com, Binance and Grab

Apr 2019 - Jul 2020

Condon

- Reworked LendInvest's website measurement from the ground up with 15+ custom events and triggers, bringing trust to data
- Built data warehouse connector for Google Analytics using the API
- Created and automated SEO SEMRush reports using Python
- A/B tests using **Bayesian Structural Time Series** on previous events
- Led first Data Science project, partnering with FICO. Built ETL pipeline in **Pandas** for loan defaults model and ran expert validation sessions

octopus labs Web Analyst

Sep 2018 - May 2019

Condon

- · Implemented conversion events tracking at Octopus, including creating five new custom dimensions and session id tracking.
- · Created reporting, implementing digital analytics framework and teaching Google Analytics to Design, Product and Marketing teams
- Performed data cleaning with Talend. Prepared SQL Reports

MailOnline Web Analyst

May 2017 - Aug 2018

Condon

- Fulfilling analytics requests at global level for mailonline.com's web, mobile and social channels, with more than 200M monthly active users
- Performed data mining of competitor videos and posts using Facebook Graph API and Power BI for the first time in the company
- Automated reports using VBA saving approximately 260 hours per year

SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- **Product Strategy**
- Stakeholder Management
- **Advanced Data Analysis**
- UX and UI
- Agile Project Management
 Postman
- Miro
- Jira
- Notion
- Figma
- SQL Looker

Heap

Python

SEMRush

- Salesforce
- Tableau
- **Facebook Prophet**
- **Google Analytics**
- Power BI

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Physics, 2015 University of Surrey, Surrey

Special Project - CHARM Laboratory launch at CERN - 13 Months - Coauthor of IEEE Nuclear Physics paper

Bachelor of Science, Physics, 2013 King's College London, London

Natanael Mota

linkedin.com/in/natanael-mota-b15b653a • 079 468 49 227 • nat.c.mota@gmail.com • London

Product Manager

Expert communicator with over 5 years of experience in product strategy, discovery and execution for B2B and B2C clients in Marketing, Fintech and Payments

Product Manager with deeply analytical background and expertise in driving cross-functional collaboration for complex projects spanning 1st, client and 3rd party stakeholders. Excellent analytical skills to enable quick, clear absorption of requirements so the team can focus on performance, contractual and financial deliverables. Experienced in delivering solutions that respect practises in handling PII, PCI and intellectual property data.

Languages: Portuguese (native), Spanish (conversational), French (A1, worked at **CERN** for one year).

Strategic Planning • Team Building & Leadership • User Research • Agile Development

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Product Management Notion, Jira, Miro, Figma, Postman, Salesforce

Analytics Python, Facebook Prophet, SEMRush, SQL, Google Analytics, Tag

Manager and Data Studio, Looker, Heap, Tableau

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product Manager (June 2022 - Present)

Ometria, London - Hybrid

Owning Cross Channel team, responsible for omnichannel marketing experience execution spanning of email, sms, advertising, app push and website personalisation partners. Generating product vision, strategy and analysis for message orchestration, channel optimisation and integrations that reach more than 500M customers for retailers such as Steve Madden and Sephora. Key Achievements:

- Led Ometria's onsite personalisation product discovery in a new market for the company, resulting in a **2M GBP** opportunity decision by the executive team
- Build and expand EMEA and NA technical partnerships in Ometria's ecosystem of 8 technical partnerships and more than 20 integrations
- Introduced pre-mortems and future press releases to development

Associate Product Manager (August 2020 - June 2022)

Checkout.com, London - Hybrid

Working closely together with international card scheme brands such as VISA, MasterCard and the Checkout.com internal product teams in designing and implementing world-class dispute solutions APIs for international payment processing. Producing business and functional requirements as well as inputting into technical requirements. Develop, optimise & document business processes.

Key Achievements:

- Led VISA RTSI integration project from discovery to execution. 450 hours per month in Operations time were saved in first two quarters
- Led monthly Dispute analytics discussion using automated python reports leveraging Looker, Plotly and Facebook Prophet
- Used data-led stories to get and lead key user interviews with some of our largest and busiest clients like Cripto.com, Binance and Grab

Natanael Mota

Page Two

Web and Product Analyst (April 2019 - July 2020)

LendInvest, Fitzrovia, London

Prepare organic, paid, and technical SEO research and recommendations, measuring complex events, quantifying impact and informing product strategy whilst reworking web analytics instrumentation for scale and data science on cost-effective budget. Train business members on bespoke measurement framework and audience intent. Studying Bayesian statistics and time series analysis methods to bring state-of-the-art decision support to website transformation and A/B testing.

Key Achievements:

- Reworked LendInvest's website measurement from the ground up with 15+ custom events and triggers, bringing trust to data
- Built data warehouse connector for Google Analytics using the API
- Created and automated SEO SEMRush reports using Python
- A/B tests using Bayesian Structural Time Series modelling on previous events
- Technical lead for first Data Science project at LendInvest, partnering with FICO. Built ETL
 pipeline in Pandas for loan defaults model, ran expert validation sessions on Plotly dashboard

Web Analyst (September 2018 - May 2019)

Octopus Labs, Holborn, London

Fostered data relationship between marketing, product and design, overseeing analytics for all Octopus Group web properties. Transformed culture for marketing teams to focus on measurement using detailed data studio reports and by making the design team more data aware as well.

Key Achievements:

- Implemented conversion events tracking at Octopus, including creating five new custom dimensions and session id tracking.
- Created reporting, implementing digital analytics framework and teaching Google Analytics to Design, Product and Marketing teams
- Performed data cleaning with Talend. Prepared SQL Reports.

Web Analyst (September 2018 - May 2019)

Mail Online, South Kensington, London

Supported Head of Analytics with data management and analysis, fulfilling requests at global level requiring clear communication with colleagues at all seniority levels across UK, US and AU. Avid advocate of Avinash Kaushik's idea of actionable insight, maintaining team's knowledge base.

Key Achievements:

- Fulfilling analytics requests at global level for mailonline.com's web, mobile and social channels, with more than **200M monthly active users**
- Performed data mining of competitor videos and posts using Facebook Graph API and Power BI for the first time in the company
- Automated reports using VBA saving approximately 260 hours per year

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Physics, 2015

Special Project - CHARM Laboratory launch at CERN - 13 Months - Paper published on IEEE University of Surrey, Surrey

Bachelor of Science, Physics, 2013

King's College London, London